<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rstats on Knut Behrends Personal Blog, v3</title>
    <link>/tags/rstats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rstats on Knut Behrends Personal Blog, v3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2018 Knut Behrends</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rstats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing 33C3 and 34C3 tweets</title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/tweets-33c3-vs-33c4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/tweets-33c3-vs-33c4/</guid>
      <description>Why this analysis? There are two reasons:
 learn to process Twitter data at scale (~100MB-1GB/file - that’s large enough for me) get more info from/about the inspiring tweets from the CCC community  (This blogpost ist still a DRAFT - I want to publish quickly, even when an analysis is incomplete, or the text is a bit rough in places)
 Background Occasionally, over the last two years, I have gathered data from the Twitter Streaming API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/constructing-a-tiny-social-network-visualization-from-the-rstats-hashtag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/constructing-a-tiny-social-network-visualization-from-the-rstats-hashtag/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of ~1000 tweets about the R language. Visualing the interactions of the active Twitter users as a directed graph. (Draft)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constructing a tiny social-network visualization from the #Rstats hashtag</title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/constructing-a-tiny-social-network-visualization-from-the-rstats-hashtag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/constructing-a-tiny-social-network-visualization-from-the-rstats-hashtag/</guid>
      <description>(Under Construction) In 2016, I was harvesting tweets from the Twitter streaming API. I’ve used the #rstats hashtag as the search filter. This hashtag is commonly used by the R community on Twitter. Tag #rstats is more descriptive than the too short, unusable, #R hashtag which may not even be a valid filter expression.
Here I do some exploratory analysis of these ~ 1000 tweets, and I visualize the interactions (the “mentions”) of the active Twitter users as a directed graph.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>