<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal Blog on Knut Behrends Personal Blog, v3</title>
    <link>/categories/personal-blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal Blog on Knut Behrends Personal Blog, v3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2018 Knut Behrends</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/personal-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Interest in Bitcoin over Time</title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/bitcoin-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/bitcoin-interest/</guid>
      <description>Visualizing (1) Wikipedia Pageviews, (2) Google Searches and (3) Exchange Rates from 2015 to early 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global interest in Bitcoin over Time</title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/bitcoin-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/bitcoin-interest/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Bitcoin. Visualizing (1) Wikipedia Pageviews, (2) Google Searches and (3) Exchange Rates from 2015 to early 2018. Simple timeseries plots (created from Web-API data) show that these three are strongly correlated.  In this post I’ll analyse global interest in Bitcoin and Ethereum over time, according to accesses to Wikipedia articles and as Google Searches.
The end of the year 2017 saw the “Bitcoin Bubble”, a period of one month where 1 Bitcoin was traded for up to $20000 on most exchanges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing 33C3 and 34C3 tweets</title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/tweets-33c3-vs-33c4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/tweets-33c3-vs-33c4/</guid>
      <description>Why this analysis? There are two reasons:
 learn to process Twitter data at scale (~100MB-1GB/file - that’s large enough for me) get more info from/about the inspiring tweets from the CCC community  (This blogpost ist still a DRAFT - I want to publish quickly, even when an analysis is incomplete, or the text is a bit rough in places)
 Background Occasionally, over the last two years, I have gathered data from the Twitter Streaming API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Gists</title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/some-gists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/some-gists/</guid>
      <description>Link Collection for my own personal use Github ‘Gists’ are code samples that are too short for, or not worth creating a new standalone repository.
For example
 One-off scripts unfinished/half-working scripts forked github gists from other people copies of codesamples from other people, slightly edited or customized  This webpage is just for my own personal use, a reminder for myself.
For now, I list only the links to the gists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning jq</title>
      <link>/post/2017/12/learning-jq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/12/learning-jq/</guid>
      <description>A grabbag of commands  Some notes about learning jq, the lightweight and flexible command-line JSON processor. I&amp;apos;ll extend and improve this blog post in the next months, in Q1/2018. This page is a notepad for my own use, it has not the purpose to teach anyone. I need to be fluent with the JSON parsing tool jq. Very often I have to interact with JSON data: When I interact with APIs, when parsing scraped Twitter data, when doing SPARQL queries…</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>